<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DPhil Projects on SABS:R&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
    <link>https://sabs-r3.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DPhil Projects on SABS:R&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Oxford</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 11:52:18 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sabs-r3.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Antibody structure modelling</title>
      <link>https://sabs-r3.github.io/projects/james-dunbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sabs-r3.github.io/projects/james-dunbar/</guid>
      <description>A project which examined how antibody orientation affects binding properties.
James’ research has dealt with understanding the structural properties of antibodies to help improve modelling and inform engineering of these therapeutically important molecules. To aid these goals he developed a database (SAbDab – Dunbar et al 2014. NAR) to collect, curate and present all publicly available antibody structural data. Last year he spent time at Roche’s Penzberg site integrating SAbDab with their in-house structure database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying diseases using Protein Interaction Networks</title>
      <link>https://sabs-r3.github.io/projects/malte-luecken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sabs-r3.github.io/projects/malte-luecken/</guid>
      <description>Building community detection methods.
When investigating the causes for a complex disease, a standard approach is to find genes which have differential expression patterns depending on whether or not test samples exhibit the disease phenotype. These differentially expressed genes are regarded to encode for proteins which are relevant to the underlying biological process. While important individual proteins may be discovered via this approach, the biological function or pathway which is regulated by these proteins cannot be understood without the context in which the proteins act to perform said function.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>